在2013年的六月中，每天就有150万台
As of July of 2013, one and a half
新的android设备被激活
million new Android devices were being activated every day.
这在几年前是难以置信的，
So it's hard to believe that just a few
我开始和那些具有潜能的开发者开会并解释
years ago, I started all meetings with potential developers explaining
什么是Android然后说服他们
what Android was and convincing them that it was
现在是android的时代，我们应该在这个的平台上努力发展。
worth their time and effort developing for the platform.
到了2010年，我们甚至分享了数字
It wasn't until 2010 that we even shared numbers
去表明这个平台的成长，那就是在那一年的三月份每一天就会有10万的激活量。
to indicate the growth of the platform, 100,000 daily activations
在2011年中期快速增长到
in May of that year. Which quickly grew to
500000并且在2012年的时候直接超过日激活量百万这个目标。
500,000 in mid-2011 and crossed the million daily activations mark
这就是为什么我在开始演讲的时候问房间
in 2012. That represents over a billion Android devices around
里的每一个人是不是都有一台Android设备，因此这也代表了
the world, which is why I don't start my presentations
全球超过十亿的Android设备。
asking if anyone in the room has an Android device
对于我来说，在那初期阶段最让我大吃一惊的就是
anymore. To me though, the biggest surprise in those early
要付出那么多的努力去说服这些
days was how much effort was required to convince people
为移动端开发的人们，让他们认为这是一个值得做的投资。
that developing for mobile at all was a worthwhile investment.
大部分人用他们的手机
A huge number of people use their phones to go
去上网，他们中的一部分则是把手机当作主要的渠道去上网。
online and many of them use their phone as the main
在2013年的皮尤互联网项目的一个研究中
way to do so. One study by the Pew Research
发现将近三分之二的手机用户
Internet Project in 2013 found that nearly two-thirds of mobile owners
用他们的手机上网，是2009年的两倍
use their phones to go online, double the rate found
还有另外的三分之一的手机用户则总是
in 2009. And that a third of phone users use mostly
用他们的手机在线。沉思一下.......
their phone to get online. Think about that for a second.
这些手机将成为口袋中的电脑并且不断的连接到
These portable phones have become pocket computers constantly connected to the
云端，然后可以让我们近距离接触或者是一目了然
cloud to make the sum of human knowledge available
所有的知识。那么
to us at a touch and a glance. It's no
对于越来越多的人们来说这也不足为奇，
wonder then that for a growing number of people,
当你离开你的办公桌的时候手机就可以继续在线
mobile isn't how to get online when you're away from
这确实是取代了个人电脑，成为了他们的主要计算平台。
your desk. It's actually displacing PCs as their primary
这个改变是多么的戏剧化，这种趋势
computing platform. The change is so dramatic and the trend
也是非常明了就像谷歌公司，他就是全身心投入在因特网上，
so clear that companies like Google, who depend entirely on
还有一个手机第一政策，就是在做一个新的产品时
internet, have a mobile first policy, ensuring that the
移动体验是首要考虑的方面。
mobile experience is the first consideration when building
这一趋势在刚刚长大并且使用手机的年轻用户
new products. This trend is particularly evident amongst younger
中尤为明显，特别是
users who grew up using mobiles and especially
在非洲和亚洲这些新兴市场，在这些地方用
in emerging markets like Africa and Asia, where the
无处不在的宽带基础设施来支持桌面是不太现实的。
infrastructure to support ubiquitous broadband for desktops isn't
就在几年前我有幸访问肯尼亚的时候
as readily available. I saw this firsthand when I
我就亲眼见过这样的
had the good fortune to visit Kenya a
事情。到处都是手机和热情，可是有才的开发者
few years ago. Ubiquitous phones and passionate, talented developers
却无处可寻，然而真正打动我的是
weren't really familiar, but what really struck me was the degree
手机已经成为人们日常生活
to which mobile phones had become an integral part of people's
必不可少的一部分。他并不仅仅是用来看个邮件，或者在脸谱网上发点东西
everyday lives. It wasn't just checking email and posting to Facebook,
从杂货到车票，她还被用来（未知）购买任何东西。
it was using [UNKNOWN] to buy everything from groceries to bus
我听到的是手机是生活的一部分，
fare. Mobiles was such a part of life that I heard
而不是你对买喝的人感兴趣，
rather than buying someone a drink to show that you're interested,
你就给他一张电话信用卡以便他们以后如果
you'd send them a phone credit so that they can call
也想给你打电话的时候可以打给你。智能手机从
you if they felt the same way. In the transition of
技术附件过渡到生活的一部分的主要
smartphones from tech accessory to a part of life to the
方式就是你要通过上网来完成支付，
main way you get online to how you pay for things,
甚至是调情，这就代表着给我们这些作为开发者们的一个巨大机会。
even how you flirt, represents a huge opportunity for us as
那么问题来了，你将如何改变世界呢？
developers. The question is, how are you going to change the world?